findaphd.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Statement - Find A PhD

## At FindAUniversity Ltd we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy relates to the following websites (hereafter referred to as ‘our websites’):

This policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our websites, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure. 

We may change this policy from time to time, so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this policy.

Any questions regarding this policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8ae3e4ece5caece3e4eeebffe4e3fceff8f9e3fef3a4e9e5e7) or in writing to FindAUniversity Ltd, 77 Sidney Street, Sheffield, S1 4RG, UK. Alternatively, you can phone us during UK office hours on +44 (0)114 268 4940.

FindAUniversity Ltd act as the data controller of the personal data you provide through our websites and their subpages. You can browse all of our websites without providing us with your personal data. If you wish to contact the organisations listed on our websites, sign up to one of our events or receive our regular newsletters then we will need your personal information. Most organisations listing on our websites include a weblink and you can use this without the need to provide us with your personal information.

You can jump to a relevant section of this Privacy Policy by following the links below: 

1\. What information do we collect and what is it for and what do we do with it?

  * Sending an enquiry to an organisation advertising on our websites
  * Registering for one of our newsletters
  * Registering for one of our postgraduate fairs
  * Completing a survey

2\. Visiting our websites / Cookie Policy

3\. Do we disclose information to outside parties?

4\. Will we transfer your information outside of Europe?

* * *

## What information do we collect and what is it for and what do we do with it?

We collect information from you when you subscribe to one of our newsletters, register for one of our events, send an enquiry to a university or other education provider, or complete a survey. Unless stated otherwise, the legal basis for processing your data is your consent and this is something you can withdraw at any time (see our contact details above or at the bottom of all our web pages).

### Sending an enquiry to an organisation advertising on our websites

#### What

There is some information that you must provide when requesting more details on the opportunities listed on our websites. We need to pass on your name, contact details, current country of residence, nationality and your education intentions. We’ll also pass on the name of the course you are interested in.

You will also be asked to select from a list of topics you’d like further information about, to include a message to the university stating your enquiry and may have the opportunity to include an attachment (for example a CV).

All this information is used by the university to provide you with the best response to your enquiry.

#### Where is it stored?

We store all email enquiry data securely on our own servers. We may provide access to a copy of your enquiry to the receiving course provider in their secure, password protected account on our websites (we do not pass on your contact details to any other third party, unless legally required to do so).

The data submitted in your enquiry is sent by email to the course provider and also securely stored on FindAUniversity Ltd servers. The course provider will respond to your enquiry directly and is responsible for gaining your consent to store or process your data further. Some course providers choose to receive copies of their enquiries each month delivered to them in a password protected file by email.

#### How do we keep your information safe?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit or access it via our websites. This includes SSL (secure sockets layer) technology to ensure that your information is transmitted safely across the internet.

When you submit an email enquiry via our websites it is subject to the same levels of security as any standard email message. This means that the email could be intercepted and read by a third party.

#### How long do we keep your data?

We keep a record of your enquiry on our system for 18 months, after which all personally identifiable data will be removed.

#### Can I access my data?

You can choose to get access to your enquiry history by writing to us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#f39a9d959cb3959a9d9792869d9a859681809a878add909c9e)

### Registering for one of our newsletters

#### What?

There is some information that you must provide us with to start receiving our newsletters. We need your name, contact details, city, current country of residence and your education intentions. We’ll also need you to confirm which newsletters you wish to receive (PhD, Masters, MBA).

In addition, we will ask you information about your date of birth, nationality, location and education history. Providing this information will improve the relevance of the information in the newsletter you receive, but they are optional fields and you’re free to keep this information to yourself.

When you register for our newsletter we will ask if you want to receive text message reminders about postgraduate study events near you. If you do then we will ask for your mobile phone number. This is the only purpose for which we will use your mobile phone number. We only use reputable thrid party services to send these text messages. Our current provider is TxtLocal Ltd (you can view their privacy statement at <https://www.textlocal.com/legal/privacy/>). 

#### Where is it stored?

We store all our newsletter subscriber data securely on our own servers. We do not pass on your contact details to any third party, unless legally required to do so.

If you have signed up to receive text alerts about events then we will use TxtLocal Ltd to send these alerts. Your number will be removed from their system after each send. TxtLocal maintain an opt-out list on our behalf for all subscribers who no longer wish to receive these text reminders. The legal basis for processing this data is your consent.

#### How can I opt out or change my subscription preferences?

You can opt out of our newsletters or change your subscription preferences by clicking the link at the bottom of any email you receive from us.

#### How do we keep your information safe?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit or access it via our websites. This includes SSL (secure sockets layer) technology to ensure that your information is transmitted safely across the internet. You can access your preferences relating to our newsletter service without the need for a password by means of an encoded link included in our communications to you. If you wish you may add a password to your account to add a further layer of security. 

#### How long do we keep your data?

We keep your newsletter subscription active for up to 3 years, after which your details will be deleted from our systems.

#### Can I access my data?

You can edit or update your data at any time by clicking the link at the bottom of any email you receive from us.

### Registering for one of our postgraduate fairs

#### What?:

There is some information that you must provide us with to register to attend one of our education fairs. We need your name, contact details, current country of residence and your education intentions. We’ll also need to know which fair you want to attend.

In addition, we will ask you information about your date of birth, nationality, location and education history. Providing this information will help us assess who we are attracting to our fairs and to improve our communications for future events. It also makes it easier for you to pass this information on to the universities that you choose to talk to at the event.

We will contact you with relevant pre-event information several times before the event. We may also contact you once after the event to request feedback on the event or for details of why you chose not to attend. This is to help us improve future events.

The legal basis for processing is our legitimate business interest, although this is something you can withdraw from at any time (see our contact details above or at the bottom of all our web pages).

When you register for our newsletter we will ask if you want to receive text message reminders about postgraduate study events near you. If you do then we will ask for your mobile phone number. This is the only purpose for which we will use your mobile phone number. We only use reputable thrid party services to send these text messages. Our current provider is TxtLocal Ltd (you can view their privacy statement at <https://www.textlocal.com/legal/privacy/>). 

#### Where is it stored?

We store all our event registration data securely on our own servers. 

At the event you can pass on the details associated with your event registration to the exhibitors you speak to by letting them scan your badge. This is designed to save you time at the event. Exhibitors will only get access to your data if you allow them to scan your badge and tick a consent statement whilst at their stand.

If you have signed up to receive text alerts about events then we will use TxtLocal Ltd to send these alerts. Your number will be removed from their system after each send. TxtLocal maintain an opt-out list on our behalf for all subscribers who no longer wish to receive these text reminders. The legal basis for processing this data is your consent.

We do not pass on your contact details to third parties under any other circumstances, unless legally required to do so.

#### How can I opt out?

You can opt out of our communications relating to the event/s you have registered for by clicking the link at the bottom of each email. If you pass on your details to an exhibitor at our events, opting out from further communications from them is between you and the organisation concerned – they will operate their own privacy policy.

#### How do we keep your information safe?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you submit or access it via our websites. This includes SSL (secure sockets layer) technology to ensure that your information is transmitted safely across the internet. Universities will only get access to your data if you allow them to scan your badge and tick a consent statement whilst at their stand.

#### How long do we keep your data?

We keep your registration active for 13 months from the date of the event you registered for (unless you have also signed up to one of our newsletters) years. We may contact you about other education events during this period.

#### Can I access my data?

If you have also signed up to one of our newsletters, you can edit or update your data at any time by clicking the link at the bottom of any email you receive from us. Otherwise please contact us to make any changes.

### Completing a survey

Occasionally we may give visitors to our websites or those who have signed up to our newsletter the chance to take part in relevant surveys. Typically, a survey will ask for some brief demographic details and will then go on to ask about your opinions and intentions relating to education choices. If there is an incentive for completing the survey (such as the chance to win an online gift voucher), then you will also have the opportunity to supply an email address. All survey data will only be processed anonymously, and no contact details will not be passed on to any third party.

#### Where is it stored:

We use industry standard and widely trusted survey platforms. We currently use SurveyMonkey.com. You can see SurveyMonkey’s privacy policy at <https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/>.

#### How do we keep your information safe?

Access to raw survey data is password protected. Visit <https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/> for the SurveyMonkey privacy policy.

#### How long do we keep your data?

We keep your survey responses in an anonymised format indefinitely. All personally identifiable information is deleted after 12 months, unless stated otherwise.

#### Can I access my data?

If you provided us with an email address when you completed the survey, then we will be able to access this data for you and remove it if required.

* * *

## Visiting our websites / Cookie Policy

We use technologies such as cookies to customise content and advertising, to provide social media features and to analyse traffic to our websites. We also share information about your use of our site with our trusted social media, advertising and analytics partners.

When you first visit our websites a direct link to this section of our Privacy Policy is provided. By continuing to use our website you consent to Cookies being used, however you may choose to use our sites without cookies (click here to see how). Not all the functions of our websites will work with cookies disabled.

### What are 'cookies'?

'Cookies' are small text files that are stored by the browser (e.g. Chrome or Safari) on your computer or mobile phone. They allow websites to store such things as user preferences. You can think of cookies as providing a "memory" for the website, enabling it to recognise a user and respond appropriately.

### How do our web sites use cookies?

A visit to a page on our websites may generate the following types of cookie:

  * Navigation cookies
  * Anonymous analytics cookies
  * Login cookies
  * Remarketing Cookies
  * Advertising cookies
  * Third-party cookies
  * User Experience Cookies

#### Navigation cookies

This type of cookie remembers where you’ve been on our websites and what you’ve searched for so the things like pressing the ‘back’ button on your browser will work properly. They are also used to record any courses that you shortlist.

#### Anonymous analytics cookies:

Every time a user visits our websites, Google Analytics generates an anonymous analytics cookie.

These cookies can tell us whether or not you have visited the site before. Your browser will tell Google Analytics if you have these cookies, and if you don't, it will create a new one. This allows us to count metrics such as the number of unique users we have, how many pages each user visits and how often.

These cookies are not used to identify individuals and are used only to generate statistics.

#### Login cookies

When you login to our websites, we set a cookie that recognises whether you are logged in or not.

#### Remarketing Cookies

Our websites use remarketing services to advertise on third-party websites (including Google, Facebook, Instagram and LinkedIn) to previous visitors to our sites. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on your Facebook timeline, in the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to our websites. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and that of either Google, Instagram, Facebook or LinkedIn. You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Preferences page (https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated), and if you want to you can opt out of interest-based advertising entirely by turning off cookies (see below).

#### Third-party cookies

On some pages of FindAUniversity Ltd’s websites, third parties may set their own anonymous cookies, for the purposes of tracking the success of their application, or customising the application for you. FindAUniversity Ltd cannot access these cookies.

For example, when you share a course using a social media sharing button on FindAMasters.com, the social network that has created the button will record that you have done this.

#### User Experience Cookies

We use [Hotjar](https://www.hotjar.com/) in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

### How do I turn cookies off?

It is usually possible to stop your browser accepting cookies, or to stop it accepting cookies from a particular website. Be aware that if you turn off cookies some of the functions on our websites will no longer work, however you will still be able to send enquiries to organisations listing on the websites.

Most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These are usually found in the 'preferences' or 'options' menu of your web browser. Use the 'Help' option in your browser for more details or try the following links.

If you are primarily concerned about third party cookies generated by advertisers, you can turn these off by going to the Your Online Choices site.

You can also visit the trade body representing these advertising platforms for more information: Network Advertising Initiative. They have provided a one-stop place that gathers all of the opt-out controls. Please bear in mind that the are many more networks listed on this site than those that we use at FindAUniversity Ltd.

To talk to us about FindAUniversity Ltd’s use of cookies then please contact [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#7e171018113e1817101a1f0b1017081b0c0d170a07501d1113)

* * *

## Do we disclose information to outside parties?

We do not sell transfer or otherwise transfer to third parties except under the following circumstances:

  * If you send an email enquiry via our website, then your details are transferred to the educational institution you are corresponding with
  * If you allow an exhibitor at one of our events to scan your badge then your data will be passed on to the education provider education provider concerned
  * We may release your information when we believe it is necessary to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

* * *

## Will we transfer your information outside of Europe?

When you contact a university outside of the EU/EEA then your enquiry data will be passed to them. Data protection rules outside of the EU/EEA vary, however we will inform these third-parties that data received from us should be treated in line with EU GDPR regulations.

Thank you for using our web sites.

This policy was last updated on 22nd Oct 2018
